[Heiji Kozenigata is a hard-boiled detective in pursuit of Chogoro the Foxfire.]
[When the authorities are warned that the Golden Fried Tofu Statue is going to be stolen, he violates his suspension and rushes to the scene.]
["Hard-Boiled Eggs Don't Crack"]
(ｴﾝｼﾞﾝ音)
(同心)おい なんだ？ この音は｡
(同心)外からか？
Hey, what's that sound?
Is it coming from outside?
(神楽)あ～れ～！
Arley!
うわぁ！
(神楽)だびっどそん!!
Davidson!
(同心)し… 侵入者です!!
正面玄関から！
A-An intruder! From the front door!
(上司)狐か！
(同心)いえ 全身ﾀｲﾂです｡
Is it the Fox?!
No, she's wearing full body tights!
えぇ!? ﾀｲﾂ？ なんで!?
(同心)なんか暴走してます！
What?! Tights?! What's going on?!
She's on a rampage-shouting things like she can't control her youthfulness!
ｵﾚの青春は
止められねえ的なことを➡
叫んでるような気がします！
She might be heading for Mt. Fuji!
[Note: Biker gangs in Japan often drive to Mount Fuji for meetings.]
富士山に
向かってるかもしれません｡
What's with that offbeat description of her rampage?
ちょ… なに？
そのﾘｱﾘﾃｨある暴走！
I may not look it, but I used to be a bad dude.
こう見えて
昔は悪かったんですよ ｵﾚ｡
そういうことを言うﾔﾂに限って
たいしたことはねえんだよ！
People who talk like that are usually the ones who haven't done much.
｢…｣とか ｢…｣とか｡
You know, like **** and ****.
Should you be mentioning names?
…やばくねえ？ その名前｡
(上司)ええい！ この際かまうな！
Never mind! Arrest anyone who looks suspicious! Alert mode, on!
怪しいもん すべて
ひっ捕らえるんだ！
警戒ﾓｰﾄﾞ ｽｲｯﾁｵﾝ！
(同心)了解!!
Roger that.
(警告音)
Today, the game is over! Full-body tights!
(上司)今日こそ
年貢の納めどきだ！ 全身ﾀｲﾂ!!
(同心)いえ 狐です！
No, it's the Fox!
(新八)本格的に
動き出したみたいですよ｡
Looks like they're moving out in full force.
(銀時)おいおい こんな騒ぎじゃ➡
Come on, if they attract too much attention, won't the Fox tuck his tail and run?
狐も ｼｯﾎﾟ巻いて
逃げちまうんじゃねえのか？
(ﾊｼﾞ)ｿｲﾂは ないと思うでやんす｡
I don't think that'll happen.
(ﾊｼﾞ)わざわざ犯行予告を
送りつけてくるくれえだ！
He went to the trouble of announcing his crime.
これくらいの警備体制
狐も予想しているはずでやんす｡
The Fox would have anticipated this level of security.
《小銭形:ﾔﾂは 必ず来る｡
He'll come for sure. A man always needs to expose himself to danger...
男とは 常に 危険に
身をおかねば生きられない｡
血に飢えたｹﾀﾞﾓﾉなのだ｡
He's a bloodthirsty beast that can't live without it.
おい 隠れろ！
何やってんだよ お前!!
Hey! Hide! What're you doing?!
なんで ﾜｲﾝ飲んでんだよ！
What're you drinking wine for?!
This isn't wine It's Camus.
(小銭形)ﾜｲﾝじゃない… ｶﾐｭだ｡
I just can't stop shaking.
さっきから震えが止まらない｡
どうやらｵﾚのなかの野獣も
居ても立ってもいられず➡
Seems the beast inside of me is getting antsy, as well.
暴れ出したようだ… ｳｪ～ｯ！
完全にﾋﾞﾋﾞってますよ！
吐くほどｶﾞﾁｶﾞﾁになってますけど…｡
He's totally scared-scared so stiff he's puking.
ﾊﾞｶだろう お前…
いいかげん ﾜｲﾝ飲むの やめろ｡
You're a fool. Stop drinking that wine already.
もう お前が ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞじゃ
ないことは みんな知ってるから｡
We all know you're not really hard-boiled.
ﾜｲﾝじゃない!! ｶﾐｭ… ｹﾞ～ｯ！
This isn't wine. It's Camus.
ｶﾐｭでもｱﾑﾛでもいいから
酒で 緊張 紛らわすのやめ…｡
Camus, Amuro, what's the difference?
[Note: Amuro is a main character from the first GUNDAM. Camus is a main character from Z GUNDAM.]
Stop using alcohol to get rid of your jitters!
ｳｪ～ｯ！
あぁ！ 銀さん!!
Gin-san, please get a hold of yourself! You're puking...
しっかりしてください！
もらいｹﾞﾛ… ｹﾞ～ｯ…｡
ちょっと
しっかりしてくださいよ！
C'mon, pull yourselves together. Ugh, what an awful sour smell!
うわっ 酸っぱくさっ！
何やってるでやんすか ｱﾝﾀら！
(同心)そこで 何をやっている!!
What's the matter with you people?!
What're you doing there?
あっ…｡
おっ!? なんだ ﾊｼﾞか｡
Huh?
It's you, Haji?
こちら異常なしでありやす！
There's nothing suspicious over here!
何か におうな…
今 誰か いなかったか？
Something smells...
Didn't I just see someone?
(ﾊｼﾞ)いえ… ｱﾁｷだけでやんす！
No, it was just me.
Haji, weren't you taken off duty today?
というか ﾊｼﾞ！ お前 今日
警備から外されてなかったか？
いえ！ 狐が来ると聞きやして
居ても立ってもいられず…｡
No, I couldn't stay home knowing the Fox is showing up.
(同心)仕事熱心なﾔﾂだなぁ｡
You're quite the go-getter.
(ﾊｼﾞ)あぁ！
そっちは 調べやしたよ！
Uh! I already checked over there.
♪♪～
《やべっ！ やべえよ…
ﾊﾞﾚる ﾊﾞﾚる!!
This is too close...too close. They'll spot us.
新八！ ﾃﾒｴ ﾒｶﾞﾈ 外せ!!
Take off those glasses. What're you wearing glasses with armor for?!
なんで鎧で ﾒｶﾞﾈなんだよ！》
《ﾒｶﾞﾈは 目の鎧です》
Glasses are armor for the eyes.
(銀時/新八)はぁ… 助かった…｡
We're sa...
...fe...?
(同心)おい こんな像 あったか？
(同心)これ 家康像じゃ？
Do you remember a statue like this?
That's a statue of Leyasu.
(小銭形)ﾋﾟﾝﾎﾟﾝﾊﾟﾝﾎﾟﾝ…｡
Pin pon pan pon.
こちらの像は 家康公鷹狩りの折➡
You are looking at a statue of the moment when a hard-boiled assassin
一瞬の隙をつき背後をとった➡
ambushed Lord Leyasu during an unguarded moment while the lord was hawking.
暗殺者のﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙ像です｡
There's...
(銀時/新八)
あるか～！ んな像!!
no such statue!
(同心)小銭形！ ｷｻﾏ～ 謹慎中に➡
Kozenigata! Damn you!
You're on suspension! What're you doing here?!
こんなところで
何をやっとるか～！
ふぅ～… ﾁｯ こうなっちまったら
是が非でも 狐 捕らえて➡
Tsk, now I'll definitely be fired unless I apprehend the Fox and restore my honor.
名誉挽回せんと 確実にｸﾋﾞだな｡
ﾌﾝ… 望むところさ｡
Hmph, I'm looking forward to it.
よし いったん ﾊﾞｰに引き返して
態勢を立て直すぞ！
Okay, let's head back to the bar and regroup.
全然 望んでねえだろ！
逃げ腰だろうが!!
You're not looking forward to it at all! You're running away!
だいたい何だよ いったん ﾊﾞｰって｡
What do you mean, "head back to the bar"? We never went to a bar!
ﾊﾞｰなんて １回も行ってねえよ！
あれ しみったれた屋台だろうが!!
That was a cheap roadside drinking stand!
(小銭形)あれがﾊﾞｰだ…
ｵｼｬﾚなﾊﾞｰは緊張して入れない｡
That's a bar. I can't go into fancy bars-they make me nervous.
ｵﾒｴ ﾎﾝﾄ ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞの
かけらもねえな！
You really don't have an ounce of hard-boiled in you!
あぁ！
(小銭形)ﾊｼﾞ!!
Haji!
Boss!
ｱﾆｷ！
(爆発音)
(２人)おぉっ！
(小銭形)き… 狐！
(同心)出た!! 狐が出た！
The...Fox?!
He appeared! The Fox appeared!
(同心)ひっ捕らえ…｡
Apprehend-
なっ… 一瞬で…｡
What?! In the blink of an eye!
野郎！ ﾅﾒやがって!!
That bastard!
He's mocking us!
Boss... Did the Fox...just save me...?
ｱﾆｷ！ 狐のﾔﾂ…
今のまさか ｱﾁｷを助け…｡
Hmph... No way...
《小銭形:ﾌﾝ まさか…
だが あの狐からは➡
But that Fox somehow seems familiar...
どこか懐かしい風が におった…｡
その後 ｵﾚたちは 狐を追ったが➡
We chased after the Fox, but were unable to capture him in the end.
結局 捕まえること叶わず｡
いったんﾊﾞｰに戻り
態勢を立て直すことにした》
We returned to the bar to regroup.
ﾃﾒｴ なに勝手に 話 進めてんだ！
Hey, stop going on with your story!
どんだけﾊﾞｰに行きてえんだよ！
ｵﾒｴは!!
How badly do you want to go to a bar?!
いちいち ﾊﾞｰ挟まねえと
次の行動ができねえのか！
Can't you do anything without going to a bar first?!
早く野郎 追うぞ！
After the bastard!
《小銭形:ﾊﾞｰもしくは
ﾋﾞﾘﾔｰﾄﾞなどを たしなみながら➡
We decided to regroup at a bar or while playing a game of pool.
態勢を立て直すことにした》
No playing pool, either! We're going, dummy!
ﾋﾞﾘﾔｰﾄﾞもﾀﾞﾒ！ 行きますよ ﾎﾞｹ!!
(同心)
間違いありません 狐です！
No mistake. It's the Fox.
He's made it past each of our cordons and is nearing the Golden Fried Tofu Statue.
次々に網を突破し
金の油揚げ像に近づいています｡
(上司)
やはり 数で押し切るのはﾑﾘか｡
We can't do this with sheer numbers alone.
まぁいい 金の油揚げ像へと
たどりつ着くには➡
That's all right... To reach the Golden Fried Tofu Statue, he'll have to pass several traps.
いくつものｶﾗｸﾘを
乗り越えなけりゃなんねえ！
いくら狐といえど
突破するのは不可能だ！
It'd be impossible for even the Fox to get through that.
これ 十番ﾓﾆﾀｰ！
There! On monitor 12!
仲間が襲撃を受けています！
Our fellow officers are being attacked!
Hey! The Fox is showing up on monitor 9! Who is that on number 10?
(上司)おい 狐は
九番ﾓﾆﾀｰに映ってるぞ！
(上司)十番には いったい誰が…｡
(同心)狐？
The Fox?!
ﾊﾞｶな!? 狐が もう１匹…｡
(同心)見てください 二番にも…｡
That can't be! Another Fox?!
Take a look! On number 2, as well!
(同心)おい！
五番 六番にもいるぞ！
Hey! He's on number 5 and number 6, too!
次々に ｶﾒﾗが 壊されていきます！
いったい どうなってる～!?
The cameras are being destroyed one after another!
What in hell's name is going on?!
The camera in this room is the only one left!
(同心)もう この部屋のｶﾒﾗしか
残っていません！
How can this be? What the hell's going on?!
(上司)ﾊﾞｶな！
いったい 何が起こってる～!?
Maybe you're being tricked by the Fox.
(ﾆｾ狐)狐にでも
化かされておるのではないか？
ま… 待て～！
W-Wait!
ﾀﾞﾒです 銀さん…｡
It's no use, Gin-san... We'll never catch up to him!
とてもじゃないけど
追いつけない…｡
He's just cruising! He's totally playing games with us!
ｱｲﾂ 余裕ですもん！ 完全に
ﾎﾞｸらを おちょくってます！
ふざけやがって！
ぜってえ 捕まえて➡
Play with us, will he?! I'll catch that guy and kill him no matter what!
ぶっ殺してやる～!!
It...hurts...
ぐ… ぐるじい！
It feels like no matter how much we run, we're not moving forward!
何か 全然 走っても走っても
前に 進まな～い!!
自分では
前に 進んでいるつもりでも➡
There are times when you think you're moving forward, but you're actually losing ground.
後ろに 下がっていたりする｡
結局 人生なんて
死ぬときになって➡
In the end, it's okay just as long as at the moment you die, you've advanced at least one step forward.
たった一歩でも 前進していたら
それでいいのかも…｡
Shut up! Hearing that when I'm tired makes me really angry! Die, you!
うるせえ～!! 疲れているときに
それ やられると➡
異常に 腹立つな！ 死ねよ お前!!
Calm down, Shinpachi! Don't waste your energy!
落ち着け 新八！
ﾑﾀﾞな体力を 使うな！
But this is strange-we really ought to be moving more than this!
にしても これ
いくらなんでも 進まなすぎ…！
…って これ～！
床が 後ろに流れてるぞ～!!
What is this?!
The floor is moving backwards!
Cut it out! Give me back the effort I expended!
ふざけんなよ！
今までの ｵﾚの労力 返せよ～!!
What'll we do?! We're not moving forward at all!
ちょっ…！ これ どうすんすか!?
全然 前に進みませんよ!!
あぁ～っ もう ﾀﾞﾒ～!!
Oh, I give up.
んっ？
なぁ～っ!! ちょっ… 速く！
Faster! Run faster!
速く 前 走ってください!!
We'll be skewered! Faster! The spikes are gaining on us!
串刺しに… 速く！
壁が 迫ってきます～!!
Don't ask the impossible! My legs are so wobbly, they're like Bambi's when he was born!
ﾑﾘを 言うな～!!
もう 足が ｶﾞｸｶﾞｸで➡
生まれたての ﾊﾞﾝﾋﾞなんだよ！
耳で 空も飛べねえんだよ～!!
I can't use my ears to fly, you know!
[Note: Refers to Disney's Dumbo.]
That's it! Run on the walls! Jump like Bambi!
あれですよ あれ！ 壁走り！
ﾊﾞﾝﾋﾞ… ﾊﾞﾝﾋﾞのように はねる！
うあ～っ！ 天よ～!!
Heaven...
give me strength!
我に 力を～!!
Ow, ow, ow. My crotch is going to split! It's going to split!
ｲﾀﾀﾀﾀ！
股 裂ける！ 股 裂ける～!!
なに やってんですか～!!
Wha'tre you doing?!
なぁぁぁぁ～っ!!
げぇぇぇ～っ!!
Pull me out quickly! Pull me out!
早く 抜いて！ 抜いて～!!
どわ～っ!!
Coin toss!
銭投げ～！
みんな ｵﾚに捕まるんだ！
Grab on to me, everybody!
小銭形さん！
ｱﾝﾀ やれば できるじゃ…！
Kozenigata-san! You really can succeed if you try!
うげぇ～！ からまった～!!
捕まれるか～!!
I'm tangled.
We can't grab hold of you!
どうしよう… んっ？
What'll we do?
これだ！
ﾅｲｽだ 新八！
There!
Nice, Shinpachi!
うわっ！ ちょっと ﾑﾘﾑﾘ！
定員ｵｰﾊﾞｰ！
Wait, this isn't working! Too many people! Go somewhere else!
他 行ってくださいよ…｡
そんな つれないこと言うなよ～｡
Don't be so cold, Shinpachi-kun.
新八く～ん｡
もう ﾑﾘ｡ 限界…｡
It's not going to hold! It's at its limit!
ｱﾆｷも 限界でやんす！
Boss is at his limit, too!
But I kinda like this...
でも ちょっといいかも…｡
知らねえよ！
Forget that idiot boss of yours!
ｵﾒｴんとこの ﾊﾞｶ大将は～!!
This is bad! What do we do now? Another one's coming!
やべえよ…｡ これから
どうすりゃ いいんだよ！
次 来た！
やばい！ また 何か…！
We're in trouble again...
It's old lady luck! We've got it made!
(ﾊｼﾞ)ﾗｯｷｰ！ ばばあだ！
これなら 楽勝でやんす！
つうか なんで ばばあだよ!?
なんのための ばばあだよ！
What's an old lady doing here?! Why is there an old lady?! Who slid her down here?!
誰が 流してんだ～!!
(ﾊｼﾞ)でも 助かったでやんす｡
But we're saved. I wonder where that old lady came from?
いったい
どこの ばばあなんでしょうね？
こんちきしょ～!!
Dammit! Why do we have to carry an old lady we've never seen before?!
なんで
見知らぬ 流れ者の ばばあを➡
担がなきゃ いけねえんだ！
ふざけんじゃねえよ！
Give me a break! I'm at my limit! We're ignoring the next old lady who comes down!
もう こっちも 限界なんだよ！
もう 次 ばばあ 来ても➡
絶対 無視な！ もう 知らねえ！
ばばあ ｵｰﾊﾞｰだ～!!
Forget it! I'm done with old ladies!
おい！ 今度は じじい来たぞ～！
Hey! Now it's an old man! What's going on?
どうなってんだ～!?
誰だ!? 誰の じじいなんだ!?
Who is he?! Who's old man is he?! Ignore him!
無視だ！ 見るんじゃねえ！
Don't look! We can't carry any more!
これ以上 荷物 抱え込むわけには
いかねえんだよ～!!
(おじいさん)ばあさん
さようなら｡ 愛してるよ…｡
Good-bye, dear. I love you.
じじい～!!
さよならなんて させねえぞ～!!
Old man! We won't let you say good-bye!
She's right next to you! Your old lady's right next to you! Tell her what you said!
隣です！
ばばあなら 隣に いますよ！
隣で もう一度
さっきの言葉 言ってあげて!!
Hey, what's with this?! What kind of harassment is this?
おい！ なんだよ これ～!?
何の嫌がらせだ!?
もう ちょっとした家族だぞ！
誰だ これ 流してるﾔﾂ!?
We've got a family here! Who's passing them down?!
Treat your elders with respect, dummy!
年寄りは 大事にしやがれ
ﾎﾞｹが～!!
(ﾊｼﾞ)あっ！
また 誰か 来たでやんす！
Ack! Another person is coming!
Hey!
おい！ お前 息子だろ！ ﾀﾞﾒだろ！
You're the son, right?
What's wrong with you! You should be looking after your father!
ちゃんと 親父 見てなきゃ～！
銀さん よく わかりましたね！
Gin-san, how did you know?
目尻のあたりが そっくりだろ
お父さんと！
He looks just like his father around the corners of his eyes!
(息子)父さん 母さん
遺産の話なんだがね➡
Father, Mother...about the inheritance. I've decided that I will take it all.
全部 私が
もらい受けることに なったよ｡
まぁ ｱｲﾂらも
ｺﾞﾁｬｺﾞﾁｬ 言ってたがね…｡
The others complained quite a bit, though.
He's talking about an inheritance when his father and mother are in a situation like this!
遺産の話 してますよ！
父さん 母さんが➡
こんな状態なのに～!!
ｺｲﾂは 串刺しでいいな！
We can let this one be skewered, right? Go lay a nest egg, you bastard!
ﾃﾒｴが 遺産 生み出せ ﾊﾞｶ野郎～!!
(赤ちゃん)ﾊﾞﾌﾞ～｡
なぁっ…!?
Three generations share the same eyes corners!
三世代
目尻が そっくりだろうが～!!
You have to live! No matter how evil you are, a child needs his parents!
生きろ～！ どんな 悪人でもな➡
子供にゃあ 親が必要なんだよ～!!
うわ～っ！
やばいですよ 銀さん！
It doesn't look good, Gin-san! It's almost on us!
もう 限界～！
ﾊﾞｶ野郎！
You fool! This family's lives depend on us!
ｵﾚたちの肩には
家族の命が かかってんだぞ!!
It's no use! We're going to die!
ﾀﾞﾒだ～!! 死ぬ～!!
(神楽)あ～れ～!!
Arley...
[Note: Wordplay on Harley Davidson.]
だびっどそ～ん!!
(銀時たち)うわぁぁぁ～っ!!
Davidson!
(狐)古くから 狐は➡
Since ancient times, the fox has been revered as a deity of the fields; a servant of the gods of rice.
田の神 稲尾の神の使いとして
崇められてきました｡
A Fox deity, if you will.
お稲荷さんというﾔﾂですなぁ｡
A statue of the fox's favorite food made of gold shows how popular I am in Edo.
狐の好物を
金で 作っちまうなんざ➡
江戸での 人気っぷりも
わかるというもんでしょう｡
But while people call me a god, it's interesting that others call me a monster that tricks people.
しかし 一方で
神様なんぞと 呼ばれていながら➡
その一方で 人を化かすﾊﾞｹﾓﾝなんて
呼ばれてるのが➡
狐の おもしろいところでやんす｡
The Nine-tailed fox, Tamamo-no-mae, Dakki, Houji and a variety of other scary monsters.
[Note: Tamamo-no-mae (Beautiful Fox Witch). Dakki (Fox demon). Houji was the concubine of the Ancient Chinese sovereign King You of Zhou.]
九尾狐に 玉藻前｡
姐己に 褒と
恐ろしいのが 揃っていましょう？
Is the Fox a god, or a monster? And what does that make me?
神様か ﾊﾞｹﾓﾝか…➡
はてさて あっしは
どちらで ござんしょう？
(小銭形)ほざけ 下郎め｡
Cut the crap, you lowlife!
(小銭形)ﾃﾒｴは
神でも ﾊﾞｹﾓﾝでもねえ｡
You're neither a god, nor a monster. You're nothing but a filthy burglar.
ただの こぎたねえ盗人だ！
10年に亘る 因縁！
ここで 決着を つけてやる！
We'll settle ten years of bad blood right here.
♪♪～
(小銭形)狐よ… 年貢の納め時だ｡
Fox. It's time to pay the piper. Give yourself up peacefully.
神妙に お縄を頂戴しろ｡
(狐)小銭形の旦那… その台詞➡
Mr. Kozenigata, I'm tired of hearing those same words for ten years.
10年で 聞き飽きやしたよ｡
ｱﾝﾀも しつこいお人だ｡
You're a persistent man.
何度まいても また 前に現れ
何度潰しても這い上がってくる｡
No matter how many times I give you the slip, you always show up again.
No matter how many times I knock you down, you crawl back up again.
Why don't you give up already?
もう いいかげん 諦めなさったら
どうでございやしょう｡
(小銭形)ｿｲﾂが
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞってやつさ｡
Because I'm hard-boiled.
固ゆでの卵は 簡単には潰れない｡
A hard-boiled egg doesn't crack easily.
それに ｵﾚは
盗人ってﾔﾂが嫌いでね｡
And besides, I hate thieves.
ｵﾚは ｶﾞｷの頃 盗人どもに
家族を皆殺しにされている｡
When I was kid, thieves killed my entire family.
お前と同じ 急ぎ働きの凶賊だよ｡
Evil thieves like you who wanted to get the job done fast.
そんな連中が許せなくて
こんな仕事についた｡
I couldn't forgive people like that, so I took this job.
そんなときに 妙な盗人に会った｡
But then I met an odd thief.
弱き者から 金品をせしめる
悪党だけを狙い➡
He targeted only villains who took money from the weak.
血も流さず 盗んだ金も
決して 私利私欲に使わない｡
He never spilled any blood and never used the money he stole for his own gain.
きれいさっぱり 還元しちまう｡
He gave every bit of it away.
法から はみ出そうとも
決して 自分の流儀は犯さない｡
He broke the law, but always had his own way of doing things.
義賊 狐火の長五郎｡
Chogoro the Foxfire, the chivalrous thief.
ｵﾚも あの頃は ﾍﾟｰﾍﾟｰだった｡
Back then, I was at the very bottom. I don't know how many times he frustrated me to tears.
ﾔﾂには 何度泣かされたかしれん｡
だが 何度も追ううち
ｵﾚは ﾔﾂに対して➡
But as I pursued him time after time, I began to feel something other than hatred for him.
憎しみ以外の感情も
もつようになっていた｡
ｵﾚが ずっと追いかけていたのは
盗人のお前だけじゃない｡
What I was constantly pursuing wasn't just the thief in you.
狐… なんで堕ちた？
あのお前が なんでこんな…｡
Fox...why'd you sink so low? Back then, you weren't...
Stop right there, Mister.
そこまでにしときなせえ 旦那｡
同心が 泥棒に
めったなこと言うもんじゃねえよ｡
An officer shouldn't say such things to a thief.
それに 堕ちたとは
盗人に言うこっちゃねえ｡
And besides...never tell a thief he's "sunk low."
Thieves like me were low to begin with.
あっしら盗人は はなから堕ちた
薄汚ねえ連中でございましょう｡
狐… お前…｡
Fox...you...
Exactly.
(ﾆｾ狐)そのとおり｡
うん？
(ﾆｾ狐)いくら 義賊と
もてはやされようと➡
No matter how much people make a fuss about being a chivalrous thief,
奪う盗むと
卑しき所業に変わりなし｡
it doesn't change that fact that you're robbing and stealing.
(ﾆｾ狐)殺さず犯さず
貧しき者から盗まず？
No killing, no raping, no stealing from the poor?
(ﾆｾ狐)どれほど
とりつくろったところで➡
A thief is a thief no matter how you try to sugarcoat it.
盗人は 盗人｡
なっ…｡
ｺｲﾂは…｡
They're...
狐が８匹!?
いや…｡
Eight...Foxes?
No...
あっちも含めりゃ ９…
いったいどういうこった こりゃ？
If you include that one, there are nine. What the hell's going on here?
(ﾆｾ狐)やはり ｷｻﾏの仕業か？
長五郎…｡
So it was your doing, after all, Chogoro.
出した覚えもない 犯行予告状｡
Those advance warnings of crimes that we never recalled sending...we took them as invitations to us.
必ずや
我らへの誘いの文と受け取った｡
(狐)いやいや こちとら
もうお勤めからは 手ぇ引いて➡
No, no... I retried from that line of work and was enjoying retired life.
しっとり 隠居生活
楽しんでたってえのに➡
最近 覚えのねえ罪科が
次々と増えてくもんでね➡
But then recently, crimes one after another popped up that I had no recollection of committing.
おちおち
寝てもいられねえんで➡
It bothered me so much I couldn't sleep, so I woke up.
起きちまったい！
Fox, are you suggesting the recent heinous robberies that have caused a stir on the streets
(小銭形)まさか 狐！
最近 巷を騒がす➡
凶悪な強盗事件は
お前の仕業でなく➡
weren't your doing, but rather...the work of these imposters?!
ｺｲﾂら ﾆｾﾓﾉの…!?
(ﾆｾ狐)残念ながら ﾆｾﾓﾉにあらず｡
Unfortunately, we aren't imposters.
(ﾆｾ狐)我ら すべて
狐の名と技を継ぎし者｡
We are all successors of the name and skills of "Fox."
(ﾆｾ狐)盗賊団 九尾｡
We are the Nine-Tails Gang of Thieves.
(ﾆｾ狐)古くは 戦国の世より
敵国へ間者として送られた➡
Once upon a time, during the period of warring states,
we were agents sent into enemy domains.
乱波 透波の流れをくむ
偸盗術のﾌﾟﾛ集団｡
We were a group of professionals in the art of thievery, with origins dating back to the ninja.
闇を切り裂き
この世に混沌をもたらす｡
We slash in the darkness of night, bringing chaos to the world.
So you come from the same roots as the ninja. Nasty...
忍と同じ源泉か…
ｺｲﾂは ﾀﾁが悪い…｡
腕は 最強
ｵﾂﾑは 最悪の泥棒ってわけかい｡
In other words, you're the strongest, dumbest thieves around.
(ﾆｾ狐)長五郎 古き同胞よ…
ようやく会えたな｡
Chogoro, old comrade. We finally meet again.
It's been 30 years since you disappeared in Kyoto.
京より 姿を消して30年…｡
I never imagined people would be calling you a chivalrous thief.
(ﾆｾ狐)まさか お前が 義賊などと
呼ばれるようになっていようとは｡
(ﾆｾ狐)子供１人 殺すこともできず
逃げ出した臆病者が➡
You couldn't even kill a child and ran away. My how big you've become.
偉くなったものだな｡
(ﾆｾ狐)江戸で築いた
その虚栄を崩してやれば➡
We figured if we destroyed the false image you'd built up in Edo, you'd come running.
すぐに出てくると
踏んでおったわ｡
30年前の裏切り きっちり
落とし前つけてもらおう｡
We'll make you pay the price for your betrayal 30 years ago.
裏切り？ 知らんねぇ｡
裏切りもｸｿも➡
Betrayal? I don't know anything about that. That's crap.
もともと お前たちを仲間なんぞと
思ったことは 一度もない｡
I never once thought of you as my comrades.
(ﾆｾ狐)ほざけ下郎がぁぁ!!
Shut up, traitor!
(狐)旦那方！
Gentlemen!
早く 階段へ！
The stairs! Hurry!
(ﾆｾ狐たち)おぉ～！
(ﾆｾ狐たち)ぐあぁぁぁ!!
ｶﾞｽか！
(狐)金の油揚げ像を
守る からくりでさあ！
Gas!
A trap set to protect the Golden Fried Tofu!
皆さん 早くこっちに！
早くしねえと 次のからくりが！
This way, everyone! Hurry! Hurry before the next trap engages!
(みんな)げぇぇ!!
階段が坂に～!?
The stairs turned flat!
(神楽)うわっ 油だ～！
ぎゃ～ すべるぅ～！
Oil!
I'm slipping!
こんな油まみれで落ちたら
一瞬で火達磨ですよ！
If we fall covered with this much oil, we'll be burned in an instant!
うわっちっちち！
熱い っつうか もう痛い!!
It's hot...hot... Or should I say painful!
What? Survivors!
なに？ 生き残りが！
新八！ 神楽！
Shinpachi! Kagura! Go!
いけぇ!!
(２人)うわっ！
What's the matter with you?!
何してんだ？ お前らぁ!!
Got two of them!
(神楽)２人とったｱﾙ！
狙いどおりっすね！
Just like you planned!
Perfect. Per-
完璧だな… 完ぺ…
おい やばい ２人行った！
Uh-oh! Two. Behind you! Look out!
後ろ 気をつけろ～！
逃げろ～!!
Run!
もういい 体当たりだ！
体当たりしろ！
Don't worry about anything else-just ram them! Ram them!
安心しろ
下で受け止めてやっから！
Don't worry! I'll catch you!
(ﾊｼﾞ)ええ!?
できるだけ
敵巻き込んで飛び降りてこい!!
Try to take them with you if you can!
ﾎﾝﾄでやんすね？ 絶対
絶対 受け止めてくださいよ!!
Are you sure? Absolutely? Make absolutely sure you'll catch me!
大丈夫だから 早くしろ！
You'll be fine! Hurry!
よ～し じゃ 行くでやんす！
Okay! Here goes!
へぇぇい!!
なんでだよ～!?
What was that?!
仲間に体当たりして
どうすんだ～!?
What good's it do to ram us?!
Gin-san! Haji-san! I'm falling! Kozenigata-san!
銀さん ﾊｼﾞさん！ 落ちる！
小銭形さん！
仲間が…？ しかし 敵も近い｡
My comrades!
But the bad guys are near.
ええい 迷うか 仲間が優先だ！
What the heck! Don't waver! My comrades come first!
銭な… へぇぇぇい！
Coin Toss!
Why?!
なんでだよ～！
なんで あそこで仲間に体当たり!?
Why'd you ram into your comrades?!
どんな選択肢だよ！
いや 怖かったから｡
What kind of decision is that?!
Well...because I was scared.
逃げてきたんかい！
You ran away?!
I can't keep this up! It's no use...I'm...
もう限界… ﾀﾞﾒだ このままじゃ…｡
Fox-san!
狐さん！
Grab my hand, quickly!
早くつかまりなせえ！
はっ はい…｡
O-Okay!
Fox-san!!
狐さぁあん！
Fox!
(小銭形)狐～っ！
(ﾆｾ狐)九尾が ９人で編成された➡
Did you forget the Nine-Tails were comprised of nine men?
盗賊団であることを忘れたか？
お前が抜けた穴を
埋めていないとでも？
Did you think we wouldn't have filled your spot after you left?
Sorry to inform you, but I've been following you; looking for an opening for quite some time.
悪いが はるか前より 後ろで➡
隙をうかがわせてもらったぞ｡
こうして お前の背中に
刃を突き立てる日を➡
I've been looking forward to the moment when I would thrust this blade into you.
あれから ずっと思っていた…｡
That memory is still etched in my mind.
今でも この目に
焼きついているぞ｡
押し入った屋敷の
子供と千両箱を抱え➡
I watched from behind as you took the child and a box of 1000 gold coins
我々のいる屋敷に火を放ち➡
from the mansion we broke into,
１人 逃げる お前の背中…｡
set fire to mansion while the others were still inside, and then ran off.
((母上！ 父上！
Mother! Father!
(狐)いいか この千両箱を
死んでも離すなよ｡
Listen to me. Don't let go of this box of 1000 gold coins, no matter what happens.
ｺｲﾂがあれば 親戚だろうが
他人だろうが➡
As long as you have this, no one-not your relatives nor strangers-can do anything bad to you.
お前を悪いようにするﾔﾂは
いねえはずだ｡
だが 金は
あまり一気にはたくなよ｡
But you mustn't use the money all at once. Spend it a little bit at a time as small change.
ﾁﾋﾞﾘﾁﾋﾞﾘ 小銭で渡していけ｡
いいな…？
Understand?
負けるんじゃねえぞ 男は強く…➡
Don't give up. A man must be strong.
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞに生きろ！))
Live your life hard-boiled.
Farewell.
さらばだ… うっ！
What the?!
♪♪～
Fox!
狐！
狐さん！
Fox-san!
す… すまねえです 旦那…｡
Forgive me...Mister...for not telling you until now.
今まで 黙ってて…｡
ﾌｯ… 人が悪いじゃねえか｡
That wasn't very nice.
命の恩人を いままで
さんざん追いまわしてたのか｡
So I've been pursuing the man to whom I owe my life?
(狐)へっ… 旦那の追跡なんざ
痛くもかゆくもねえや｡
Yeah...
Your pursuit didn't bother me in the least.
ｱﾝﾀは 詰めが甘すぎらあ｡
You'd always miss catching me in the end.
敵に毎日 愚痴こぼすなんざ➡
Complaining to your foe every day.
同心 失格じゃねえですかい｡
Doesn't that make you a failure as an officer?
ﾌﾌｯ… そうか…｡
I see... No wonder I could never capture you.
どうりでつかまらねえはずだ｡
ｵﾚは ずっとｱﾝﾀに…
見守られてたってわけか｡
You were...always watching over me.
旦那… ｱﾝﾀ 結局 最後まで➡
Boss...You were never able to apprehend me in the end.
あっしを
つかまえられなかったですねい｡
It was a total victory for me.
あっしの完全勝利だ！
(小銭形)いや… ｵﾚの勝ちだ｡
No, I won. I can bring you back alive.
生きて連れて帰る｡
Before you go to jail, you'll have to join me for some Camus.
牢屋に入る前に ｶﾐｭを１杯
つきあってもらうがな｡
ｶﾐｭじゃねえ… 焼酎だ｡
Not Camus.
Shochu.
《小銭形:その後 炎の跡から➡
Later, not one fox's body was found in the aftermath of the fire.
狐の遺体は １体も
見つからなかった｡
燃え尽きてしまったのか
はたまた 誰も死んでないのか｡
Were they burned to ashes, or were none of them dead?
さすがは 神出鬼没の怪盗 狐…｡
They were, after all, the elusive Foxes.
ﾔﾂが 生きているのか 死んだのか
それを知る術はない｡
There was no way to know if he was alive or dead.
だが わかっていることが
ひとつ ある｡
However, I did know one thing...
それは…》
One more place...
もう１軒 どうよ｡
(小銭形)うぷ… 気持わる…｡
I don't feel so good.
《小銭形:こんなﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞな夜は
無性に酒が欲しくなる｡
On these hard-boiled nights, I thirst for a drink.
男には 酒でしか癒やせない
傷がある》
There are wounds that a man can only heal with liquor...
(小銭形)ん…？ こんなところに
ﾊﾞｰがあったか？
Huh? Was there a bar here before?
ﾊﾞｰじゃねえよ ﾊﾟｰだろ ｱﾝﾀ ﾎﾝﾄ！
It's not a bar. You've really lost it...
(親父)へい らっしゃい｡
Welcome.
ﾏｽﾀｰ… ｶﾐｭ ﾛｯｸで頼む｡
Master... Camus, on the rocks.
へい 焼酎｡
焼酎じゃない ｶﾐｭと呼べ ﾏｽﾀｰ｡
Here you go. Shochu.
Not shochu. Call it Camus, Master.
ﾏｽﾀｰじゃねえ 親父と呼べ 旦那｡
Don't call me master. You can just call me Pops, sir.
あっ あれっ!?
Huh? That's...
ﾌｯ…｡
《小銭形:そう… ｵﾚは➡
That's right, I'm...the hard-boiled detective, Heiji Kozenigata.
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ同心 小銭形 平次》
Wh-Who are you...?
Hijikata's corpse makes 4016 bodies.
Hijikata the fool's corpse makes 4017 bodies.
Hijikata the dummy's body makes 4018 bodies.
Hijikata the moron's body makes 4019 bodies.
Hijikata the bastard's body makes 4020 bodies.
Hijikata the pile of shit's body makes...
Count sheep!
♪♪～
Huh? Morning already? I couldn't sleep at all, dammit.
Of course you can't sleep counting grotesque things like that!
Thank you. Did you come just to wake me up, body number 4021?
Who're you calling body 4021?!
Go wash your face and change right away.
There's someone to see you.
[Next episode... "It's Often Difficult to Sleep When You're Engrossed with Counting Sheep"]
(土方)ﾃﾒｴは…｡
[The visitor turned out to be Okita's sister, Mitsuba.]
[The mingling of feelings and the memory from that day...]
(沖田)土方の死体が4016体…｡
土方のﾊﾞｶの死体が4017体…｡
土方のﾎﾞｹの死体が4018体…｡
土方のｱﾎの死体が4019体…｡
土方の あんちくしょうの
死体が4020体…｡
土方のｸｿｯﾀﾚの死体が…｡
羊を数えろ！
(沖田)あれ… もう朝か｡
全然 眠れなかった ちくしょう…｡
(土方)眠れるわけねえだろ
あんな ｸﾞﾛﾃｽｸなもん 数えて！
すいやせん わざわざ
起こしにきてくれたんですかい？
4021号…｡
誰が4021号だ！
(土方)さっさとﾂﾗ洗って着替えろ｡
客だ｡